Mss.B.B28.w Mss.B.B28.w
American Philosophical Society
John Bartram correspondence, 1735-1775
Mss.B.B28.w
American Philosophical Society
719.0 Item(s)
Correspondence compiled by Edward E. Wildman and Francis D. West, chiefly from original letters in the Historical Society of Pennsylvania and other depositories, 1956.
719 items, typed. Typewritten transcript. This collection is also available on microfilm (Film 1433).
Bartram, John, 1699-1777
Breintnall, Joseph, d. 1746
Colden, Cadwallader, 1688-1776
Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
Linne, Carl von, 1707-1778
Sloane, Hans, Sir, 1660-1753
Witt, Christopher, 1675-1765
Box 4
Biographical/Historical note
John Bartram was the first native American botanist and made many journeys through the southern frontier, collecting seeds and bulbs for transplanting.
Existence and Location of Originals note
Originals of parts of this collection are in the Historical Society of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia.
Existence and Location of Copies note
This collection is also available on microfilm (Film 1433).
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Presented by Edward E. Wildman, 1956, second copy presented by W.W. Cadbury, 1956; both accessioned the same year. Deaccessioned second copy (1956 1166ms), 1982. Gift to John Bartram Association, Philadelphia.
Scope and Contents note
Among the material covered is Bartram's journey to Fort Oswego in 1743 for a treaty with the Five Nations; other references principally to Indian hostilities in South.
General note
Parts of this collection are published in William Darlington, Memorials of John Bartram and Humphrey Marshall, (Philadelphia, 1849).
Early American History Note
The John Bartram Collection consists of typed transcriptions of originals held at the Historical Society of Pennsylvania. The transcripts take up two volumes and are extensive.
Wildman, Edward, (Edward Embree), 1874-1956; Botanists.; Botany.; Colony and State Specific History; General Correspondence; Horticulture.; Horticulturists.; Natural History; Natural history.; Pennsylvania History; Philadelphia History; Plant collectors.; Plants -- Collection and preservation.; Scientific Correspondence
- Papers
  - Letter to John Bartram, Jan. 20, 1734/5; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Scope and Contents note
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 2:8. Darlington's Memorials 59.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Jan. 24, 1735; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 2:9. Darlington's Memorials 63.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 12, 1735; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:10. Darlington's Memorials 66.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 20, 1735; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:11. Darlington's Memorials 68.
  - Letter to John Bartram, March 1, 1735; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 2:12. Darlington's Memorials 69.
  - Letter to John Bartram, March 31, 1735; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 2:14.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 19, 1735; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 2:16.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 28, 1735; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 2:17.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Aug. 16, 1735; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:18. Darlington's Memorials 70.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Sept. 3, 1735; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 2:19.
  - Letter to John Bartram, March 12, 1735/36; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 4p. Bartram Papers 2:13. Darlington's Memorials 72.
  - Letter to John Bartram, April 21, 1736; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:25. Darlington's Memorials 75.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 1, 1736; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:26. Darlington's Memorials 76.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 1, 1736; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 6, 1736; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:27. Darlington's Memorials 78.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 7, 1736; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:28. Darlington's Memorials 79.
  - Letter to John Bartram, August 28, 1736; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:29. Darlington's Memorials 80.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Sept. 20, 1736; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:30. Darlington's Memorials 81.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Summer, 1736?; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 3:32.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Jan. 20, 1737; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 2:20. Darlington's Memorials 82.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 17, 1737; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 4p. Bartram Papers 2:34. Darlington's Memorials 88.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 26, 1736/7; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:21. Darlington's Memorials 90.
  - Letter to John Bartram, March 14, 1736/7; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 2:22. Darlington's Memorials 90.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Sept. 8, 1737; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 2:39. Darlington's Memorials 100.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Nov. 1737; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:38.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Dec. 10, 1737; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 2:40. Darlington's Memorials 101.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Dec. 14, 1737; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 5 p. Bartram Papers 2:41. Darlington's Memorials 103.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Dec. 20, 1737; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 5p. Bartram Papers 2:42. Darlington's Memorials 107.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Dec. 24, 1737; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 1, 1738; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Bartram Papers 2:35.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 3, 1738; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 4p. Bartram Papers 2:33.
  - Letter to John Bartram, April 6, 1738; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 4p. Bartram Papers 2:36. Darlington's Memorials 115.
  - Letter to Joseph Breintnall for John Bartram, May 2, 1738; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 3p.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, May 1738; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3 p. Bartram Papers 1:14:2. Darlington's Memorials 119.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, 1738; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:20:3.
  - Letter to Doctor J.J. Dillenius, Aug. 1, 1738; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:14:8. Darlington's Memorials 308.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Sept. 11, 1738; Dillenius, Johann Jakob, 1687-1747
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:98. Darlington's Memorials 309.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, 1738?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:38.
  - Report to [the Royal society of London?], 1738; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    ? Typed D. 3p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.79-81.) Botany. Refers to Franklin.
  - Letter to Col. William Byrd, Nov., 1738; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:14:10.
  - Letter to Col. Custise, Nov. 19, 1738; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:23. Darlington's Memorials 312.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Nov. 30, 1738; Byrd, William, 1674-1744
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:94. Darlington's Memorials 312.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, December, 1738; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:17:3 and 1:23:2. Darlington's Memorials 120.
  - Journal of a trip to Maryland and Virginia, December? 1738; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 4p. Bartram Papers 1:14:7. Darlington's Memorials 120.
  - Letter to John Bartram, January 26, 1738/9; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typred. 3p. Bartram Papers 2:43. Darlington's Memorials 123.
  - Letter to John Bartram, February 1, 1739; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:46. Darlington's Memorials 125.
  - Letter to John Bartram, February 1, 1738/9; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed 3p. Bartram Papers 2:44. Darlington's Memorials 125.
  - Letter to John Bartram, March 23, 1738/9; Byrd, William, 1674-1744
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:17:4. Darlington's Memorials 315.
  - Letter to John Bartram, April 12, 1739; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 4p. Bartram Papers 2:47. Darlington's Memorials 128.
  - Letter to John Bartram, May 20, 1739; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 4p. Bartram Papers 2:48.
  - Letter to Doctor Dillenius, 1739?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:23.
  - Letter to John Bartram, 1739?; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 3:10. Darlington's Memorials 112.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, May, 1839?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:38.
  - Letter to John Bartram, May 24, 1739; Randolph, Isahm
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:100. Darlington's Memorials 317.
  - Letter to John Bartram, May 29, 1739; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 2:49.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 6, 1739; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:50.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, 1739?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:17:3.
  - Letter to John Bartram, July 10, 1739; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 3:9. Darlington's Memorials 131.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, July 18, 1739?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:19:1.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, July 1739; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:17:1.
  - Letter to Alexander Colhoun, July 26, 1739; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:19:1.
  - Letter to John Bartram, August 18, 1739; Colhoun, Alexander
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:6. Darlington's Memorials 318.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Sept. 2, 1739; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    TYped. 4p. Bartram Papers 2:51. Darlington's Memorials 133.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, December 6, 1739; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:7.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Nov. 5, 1739; Colhoun, Alexander
    Typed. 2 p. Bartram Papers 2:7.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, late in 1739; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:20:6.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, November 1739; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:19:3.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Nov. 11, 1739; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:19:5.
  - Letter to Dr. J.J. Dillenius, Dec. 5, 1739; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:19:6.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 10, 1740; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 2:52. Darlington's Memorials 139.
  - Letter to John Bartram, July 20, 1740; Cressy, S.
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:91.
  - Letter to John Bartram, July 22, 1740; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 4p. Bartram Papers 2:53:1-4. Darlington's Memorials 136.
  - Letter to J.S. Cressy, July 24, 1740; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:20:2.
  - Letter to Isham Randolph, 1740?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:20:3.
  - Letter to Doctor Cressy, Sept. 20, 1740; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:20:5.
  - Letter to Peter Bayard, 1740?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:21, 22:5.
  - Letter to Dr. J.S. Cressy, 1740?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:23:4.
  - Letter to Mark Catesby, 1740?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:42:3. Darlington's Memorials 321.
  - Letter to John Bartram, 1740?; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 3:30-31.
  - Peter Collinson's notes, Sept. 25, 1740; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
  - Letter to John Bartram, Oct. 15, 1740; Dillenius, Johann Jakob, 1687-1747
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 3:99. Darlington's Memorials 309.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Oct. 20, 1740; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 2:54. Darlington's Memorials 137.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Dec. 20, 1740; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 2:55. Darlington's Memorials 138.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, 1740?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:18.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, 1740?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:14:5.
  - Journals of trips in Pennsylvania, Maryland, and Virginia, 1740?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:42.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 25, 1741; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Tped. 3p. Bartram Papers 2:57. Darlington's Memorials 139.
  - Letter to J.S. Cressy, March 29, 1741; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:2:3.
  - Letter to John Bartram, July 21, 1741; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 4p. Bartram Papers 2:59. Darlington's Memorials 143.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, July 22, 1741; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:21; 1-6.
  - Letter to Sir Hans Sloan, July 22, 1741; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:22:2. Darlington's Memorials 302.
  - Letter to Peter Bayard, 1741?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:22:3.
  - Letter to J.S. Cressy, Fall, 1741?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:22:5.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Sept. 1, 1741; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:60. Darlington's Memorials 144.
  - Letter to Mark Catesby, Oct. 1741; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:21:7.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Summer, 1741?; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:17.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Fall 1741?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:22:2.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, October 18, 1741; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:35:5.
  - Some Observations on Specimens, 1741; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 8p. Bartram Papers 2:75.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 2, 1742; Catcott, Alexander, 1725-1779
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:98
  - Description of a clam, 1741; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 2:62.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Feb. 3, 1741/2; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 2:56.
  - Letter to John Bartram, March 3, 1742; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 4p. Bartram Papers 2:58. Darlington's Memorials 150.
  - Letter to John Bartram, March 20, 1741/2; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 2:65.
  - Letter to John Bartram, April 25, 1742; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:66. Darlington's Memorials 153.
  - Letter to Mark Catesby, Spring, 1742; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:29:3.
  - Letter to Peter Bayard, 1742?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:20:1.
  - Letter to John Bartram, May 16, 1742; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 2:67. Darlington's Memorials 154.156.
  - Letter to Alexander Catcott, May 26, 1742; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:28:4 Darlington's Memorials 324.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, May 30, 1742; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:28:3.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, 1742?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:29:4.
  - Letter to John Bartram, July 3, 1742; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 2:68. Darlington's Memorials 157.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, July 6, 1742; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:40. Darlington's Memorials 158.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, July 24, 1742; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:40. Darlington's Memorials 159.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Sept. 5, 1742; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:28:3. Darlington's Memorials 160.
  - Letter to Doctor J.J. Dillenius, Sept. 14, 1742; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:26:2. Darlington's Memorials 310.
  - Letter to Sir Hans Sloan, Nov. 14, 1742; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:26:2. Darlington's Memorials 303.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Nov. 17, 1742; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:24:1 & 25.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Nov. 18, 1742; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:24:2.
  - Letter to Mark Catesby, Nov. 29, 1742?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:24:1.
  - Letter to Dr. Cadwallader Colden, late 1742; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:25:2.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Dec. 18, 1742; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:25. Darlington's Memorials 161.
  - Notes on the Hibernation of Bears, Jan. 16, 1743; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:26.
  - Letter to Dr. Colden, Jan. 16, 1742/3; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1 p. Bartram Papers 1:26. Darlington's Memorials 326.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, May 27, 1743; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:27. Darlington's Memorials 162.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, June 11, 1743; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p Bartram Papers 1:27:2. Darlington's Memorials 163.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, June 20, 1743; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 4p. Bartram Papers 1:15:1. Darlington's Memorials 164.
  - Letter to Dr. Colden, June 26, 1743; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:27:3. Darlington's Memorials 328.
  - Letter to Sir Hans Sloan, Sept. 23, 1743; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:24:3. Darlington's Memorials 304.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, 1743?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:24:3. Darlington's Memorials 169.
  - Letter to Sir Hans Sloan, Nov. 16, 1743; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:24:4. Darlington's Memorials 305.
  - Letter to Doctor J.J. Dillenius, Nov. 29, 1743; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:26:4. Darlington's Memorials 311.
  - Letter to Alexander Catcott, Nov. 24, 1743; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:26:3. Darlington's Memorials 325.
  - Letter to Dr. Gronovius, Nov. 30, 1743; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:24:4. Darlington's Memorials 349.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Nov. 30, 1743; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:26:4.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Dec., 1743; Fothergill, John, 1712-1780
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 4:15. Darlington's Memorials 333.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Jan. 16, 1744; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:71. Darlington's Memorials 166.
  - Letter to John Bartram, March 10, 1744; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:70. Darlington's Memorials 170.
  - Letter to Dr. Mitchell, June 5, 1744; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:27:4. Darlington's Memorials 363.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, July 24, 1744; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:40:4. Darlington's Memorials 172.
  - Letter to Dr. John Fothergill, July 24, 1744; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:28. Darlington's Memorials 337.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Aug. 5, 1744; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 2:72.
  - Letter to John Claton, Sept. 1, 1744; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:28.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, 1744; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:40.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Dec. 1744; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:29. Darlington's Memorials 173.
  - Letter to Dr. Gronovius, Dec. 8, 1744; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:31.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Dec. 1744?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:29:2.
  - Letter to Dr. Fothergill, Dec. 7, 1745; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:30. Darlington's Memorials 338.
  - Letter to Sir Hans Sloan, Dec. 8, 1745; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:30:3. Darlington's Memorials 306.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Dec. 10, 1745; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:30:3. Darlington's Memorials 173.
  - Letter to John Bartram, 1745?; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 3:33.
  - Letter to John Bartram, 1745?; Fothergill, John, 1712-1780
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 4:16.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Dec. 1745?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 1:31:3&4.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Feb. 14, 1746; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, April 12, 1746; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:30:2. Darlington's Memorials 175.
  - Letter to John Bartram, April 15, 1746; Catesby, Mark, 1683-1749
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:97. Darlington's Memorials 323.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, April 23, 1746; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:30:6. Darlington's Memorials 176.
  - Letter to John Bartram, April 20, 1746; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 2:78.
  - Letter to John Bartram, April 26, 1746; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 2:72. Darlington's Memorials 177.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 2, 1746; Gronovius, Johannes Fredericus, 1686-1762
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 4:39. Darlington's Memorials 354.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Undated; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 1:33.
  - Letter to Dr. Gronovius, Dec. 15, 1746; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 1:31:2. Darlington's Memorials 358.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Jan. 2, 1747; Mitchell, John, 1711-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:85. Darlington's Memorials 364.
  - Letter to John Bartram, March 3, 1747; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:73.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 2, 1747; Mitchell, John, 1711-1768
    Typed L. 1p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; p.280.) ----Copy under date of Jan. 2, 1747, see p.277. Refers to Franklin. Printed: Darlington, 364-366.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, July 20, 1747; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 1p. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; p.281.) Refers to Franklin. Printed: Darlington, 179-180.
  - Letter to John Bartram, 1747?; Mitchell, John, 1711-1768
    Typed L. 2p. Incomplete. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; pp.282-283.) Natural history. Refers to Franklin.
  - Letter to Peter Collinson, Jan. 30, 1748; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed L. 1p. Fragment. (see Wildman. Correspondence of Bartram; p.279.) Refers to Franklin.
  - Bartram's Comments on the sex of flowers, Undated; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
  - Letter to Carl Linnaeus, 1748?; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typed. 1p.
  - Letter to John Bartram, June 27, 1749; Dobbs, Arthur, 1689-1765
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 3:100.
  - Letter to John Bartram, 1749?; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
  - Letter to John Bartram, July 3, 1750; Poole, R.
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:96.
  - Letter to John Bartram, Jan. 20, 1751; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:84:2. Darlington's Memorials 182.
  - Letter to John Bartram, March 5, 1750/1; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 3p. Bartram Papers 2:83. Darlington's Memorials 183.
  - Letter to John Bartram, March 22, 1751; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 2:85. Darlington's Memorials 183.
  - Letter to John Bartram, March 30, 1751; Mitchell, John, 1711-1768
    Typed. 1p. Bartram Papers 4:87. Darlington's Memorials 367.
  - Letter to John Bartram, April 24, 1751; Collinson, Peter, 1694-1768
    Typed. 2p. Bartram Papers 2:86. Darlington's Memorials 183.